

### CONTACT



Address London, UK



Phone +44 (0) 7490 200466



Email nicholas.newell@protonmail.ch



in/nicholasdnewellwebdeveloper



Twitter https://twitter.com/NicholasDNewell



https://github.com/NDNewell

## **SUMMARY**

Having always had a fascination with technology and after years of experience ranging from sales to education, I am transitioning into front-end web development so that I may engage in leading edge technological development, use my creative skills in productive ways, and make or add to a substantial product or service that creates positive change in the world.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript HTML5

CSS3 iQuery

Knockout.js (MVVM)

Bootstrap

GitHub

Performance Optimization

**TDD** 

Responsive Design

Grunt

Firebase

# NICHOLAS D. NEWELL

Working rights in EU and US / Willing to relocate

# **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

MAY 2016 •

**UdaciFeeds** - http://NDNewell.github.io/frontend-nanodegree-feedreader/

- Completed testing suite using Jasmine for an incomplete project by writing tests that pass.
- Created tests that check form completion, menu changes, and proper loading of elements.
- Wrote tests that determined if web application loops and URLs function properly

FEB 2016

- SurfList https://dazzling-torch-4012.firebaseapp.com/
- From scratch, single-page, responsive app using Knockout.js and jQuery that allows users to search for surf breaks
- Utilized firebase for hosting, authentication, and backend data storage.
- Implemented third party APIs via AJAX data requests.

JUN 2015

**Website Optimization** - https://ndnewell.github.io/frontend-nanodegree-mobile-portfolio/

- Optimized critical rendering path of existing website (Cam's profile) to achieve PageSpeed Insights score above 90.
- Eliminated inefficiencies in the website's (Cam's Pizzeria) scroll animation (pizza.html). Site now scrolls at 60 frames per second
- Used JavaScript task runner Grunt in build process.

MAR 2015

**Cartman Crush** - https://ndnewell.github.io/frontend-nanodegree-arcade-game/

- Clone of the classic game, Frogger.
- Coded player, enemies, relic subclasses using object prototype chains
- Used HTML5 Canvas for game animation.



# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

MAY 2014 - MAR 2015 •

**English Language Educator** 

#### **Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology** – Hanoi, Vietnam

- Presented workshops focusing on writing for university and supported students via a university help desk.
- Taught across all levels in the academic English program, with a focus on research & report writing for academia.
- Led business English classes for locally based firms & taught government diplomatic officials job-related English.
- Successfully integrated the use of 6 new educational technology tools into teaching approach.

DEC 2012 - APR 2014

#### **English Language Instructor**

- Led upper level reading and essay/report writing lectures, with a focus on general argumentative logic.
  - Nominated teacher of the year in 2013.
- Utilized web technologies for teaching students and supporting colleagues





# **WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)**

**DEC 2011 - NOV 2012** 

**English Language Teacher** 

**ILA Vietnam** - Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Taught General English to all ages in classrooms of 12 19 students, using a student centred approach.
- Increased student participation, using culturally relevant
- Created new behaviour management techniques, resulting in an increase in overall student output.

OCT 2008 - MAR 2011 Marketing Sales Manager

SUPA-T Green Tea - Sydney, Australia

- Implemented local distribution, sales, and field marketing efforts in and around Sydney and key areas of NSW.
- Successfully acquired 2 major distributors in the Australian market, allowing broader access to cross-country markets.
- Managed the design and provided the copy for the company website, adding appeal to existing sales points.



# **EDUCATION & ACTIVITIES**

OCT 2014 - MAY 2016

Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

**Udacity** - Global

MAR 2014 - AUG 2014

**Cert ICT (Distinction)** 

**Cambridge English** – Hanoi, Vietnam

APR 2011 - MAR 2012

**YL Extension** 

Cambridge English - Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

OCT 2011 - NOV 2011

**CELTA (Pass B)** 

**Cambridge English** – Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

AUG 2002 - MAY 2006

German B.A. / Minor Business

University of Colorado - Boulder, Colorado, USA

**DEC 2002 - MAY 2006** 

Founder of the University of Colorado chapter

Sigma Alpha Epsilon - Boulder, Colorado, USA